Javier Hernandez Requena

Fremont, CA (415) 971-0621 Business.Requena@Gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Seasoned technical professional with over 10 years in Robotics, Electric & Autonomous Vehicles, Drones, Consumer Technology, and Renewable Energy. 4 years in Cyber Security & Software Development. 2 years in Content Creation & Marketing. Skilled in Hardware and Software Engineering, seeking a challenging position to apply and grow my diverse skill set and creative problem-solving attributes.

SKILLS

Strong analytical problem-solving skills, root-cause analysis, and detail-oriented approaches.

Organization & time management, problemsolving & adaptability.

Proficient in G-Suite and Microsoft Office Suite.

Knowledge of RF, ultrasonic welding, electromechanical assembly, machining, 3D printing, laser cutting, and machine shop best practices.

Hardware Engineering: mechanical, electrical, electronics, welding, composites fabrication, troubleshooting, and repair.

Team supervision, process integration, and documentation.

Hands-on experience with high and low-voltage systems, wire harnesses, electro-mechanical devices, soldering irons, DMM, oscilloscopes, and logic analyzers.

Strong knowledge of data structures & algorithms.

Product Testing: Reliability, Prototype, Environmental/Temp., Stress, Penetration testing.

Software Engineering: Linux, Mac, Windows, C++, Python, BASH, JavaScript, HTML/CSS, cyber security, web-app development.

WORK HISTORY

CONSULTANT | 06/2019 to Current Self - San Francisco Bay Area

- Delivered outstanding service to clients to maintain and extend relationship for future business opportunities.
- Consulted with clients to assess needs and propose business, marketing, and technological solutions.
- Services include: Cyber Security, Engineering, Marketing, and Business Strategy.
- Clients include: Zoox Inc., Pyka Inc., ReVamp'd Electrical Services, The Camp Transformation Fitness Center, and more.

HARDWARE RELIABILITY ENGINEERING SPECIALIST | 01/2021 to 02/2024 Tonal Systems Inc. - San Francisco, CA

- Assessed engineering data and recommended solutions.
- Conducted product testing for performance and adherence to specifications.
- Trained test technicians and operators in hardware and software.
- Gathered and analyzed data using ELK stack and OpenSearch.
- Designed & fabricated different test fixtures.
- Drove root cause analysis on reliability testing failures.
- HALT, ALT, HAST, Stress, Environmental tests and more.
- Build/assemble prototypes and sub-assemblies including electronics assembly, cabling, rework, and repair.

- Worked closely with Mechanical, Electrical, Firmware, and Reliability Engineers to conduct tests.
- Assemble lab and storage equipment.
- Disassemble and reassemble machines going through engineering testing.
- Maintaining stock of lab, hardware, and prototyping supplies.
- Used different kinds of tools to accomplish tasks and goals including MIG welder, power tools, mill & lathe, hand tools, DMM, oscilloscopes, logic analyzers, power supplies, force gauges, solder irons, Android Debug Studio, programmers, etc.
- Created standardized procedures and on-boarding documents to facilitate hiring of personnel and ensure data integrity & repeatable testing results.
- Saved company over \$1 million in material and assets by implementing automated and reproducible solutions.
- Enhanced overall team productivity through continuous improvement initiatives focused on streamlining processes and optimizing resource allocation.

PENETRATION TESTER | 02/2020 to 01/2021

ADA Corporation - San Francisco, CA

- Conducted security audits to identify, mitigate, and remediate vulnerabilities
- Engaged internal and external customers during planning and test phases to achieve goals
- Created proposals and reports for executive and board members of corporations, state, and county services.
- Stayed current on emerging threats and trends in cybersecurity, adapting testing methods as needed to address new risks.
- Mentored junior team members in best practices for ethical hacking and penetration testing techniques, fostering professional growth among colleagues.

ENGINEERING TECHNICIAN | 01/2018 to 05/2019

Saildrone Inc. - Alameda, CA

- Built, configured, and tested robots and robotic applications.
- Developed, deployed, and tested prototype systems to assess functionality and feasibility.
- Evaluated robotics systems for quality and safety controls.
- Built and integrated electronic, mechanical, and computer systems including advanced radars and sensors on drones.
- Tested features, documented findings, modeled trends and submitted reports.
- Consistently met high-quality standards for all completed work while adhering to established timelines, ensuring client satisfaction with final results.
- Contributed to a safer working environment through strict adherence to safety protocols, guidelines, and regulations.
- Streamlined workflow within the team through effective communication and collaboration with engineers, technicians, and management.
- Designed and fabricated metal test & retrofitting fixtures and stations.

ROBOTICS & ENGINEERING MAINTENANCE TECHNICIAN $\mid 05/2017 \uparrow 0 01/2018$ Amazon - Patterson, CA

- Inspected and tested machinery for diagnosing malfunctions
- Interpreted drawings, blueprints, and schematics of building and systems layout as well as robotic machinery.
- Operated varied hand and power tools to complete repairs.
- Used problem-solving skills to alleviate issues efficiently with minimal supervision.
- Followed safety protocols to minimize workplace accidents.
- Successfully completed complex repair tasks within tight deadlines, minimizing disruptions to daily operations.
- Completed daily, weekly, and monthly checklists on building equipment to maintain records of scheduled maintenance procedures.

ELECTRICIAN | 01/2016 to 05/2017

Various - Northern California

Installed and wired electrical hardware for diverse clientele, including, but not limited to: FireEye,

Tesla, Amazon, and Edgewood Resort.

- Installed and wired transformers, junction boxes, service panels, electrical boxes, switches, circuit breakers, robotic assembly lines, conveyor systems and more.
- Worked from ladders, scaffolds and lifts to install, maintain, or repair electrical wiring equipment and lighting fixtures in ceilings, on roofs and on towers.
- Planned layout and installation of electrical wiring, equipment, and fixtures based on specifications and applicable code.
- Inspected electrical systems, equipment and components to identify hazards, defects, and repair requirements.
- Used testing instruments such as ohmmeters, voltmeters, ammeters, and multimeters.
- Performed routine and complex maintenance and repairs on various electrical equipment.

PRODUCTION & PROTOTYPE TECHNICIAN | 06/2014 to 07/2015 Tesla Motors Inc. - Fremont, CA

- Production assembly of Model S Vehicles, achieving first breakthroughs of 100+ underbodies in a shift on first of its kind robotic assembly line.
- Prototype testing & assembly of Model X Vehicles before it was revealed to the public.
- Inspected machinery and robotic systems to ensure proper configuration.
- Provided valuable feedback on proposed design changes, helping to optimize products for market readiness before mass production began.
- Demonstrated proficiency in using various hand tools, power tools, and equipment necessary for assembling high-quality prototypes efficiently.

EDUCATION

City College of San Francisco - San Francisco, CA | Associate of Science

Cyber Security, 12/2022

- Dean's List 4.0 GPA
- Global CPTC Western Regional 2023 2nd Place
- Certificates: C++ Programming, Security for Web App Development

Las Positas College - Livermore, CA | Associate of Science

Engineering Technology, 01/2018

- Lawrence Livermore National Lab Engineering Technology Cohort 2017 (NIF Plasma Fusion)
- Men's Soccer Coast Conference Champion 2013 & 2016

LANGUAGES

English	Spanish
Native or Bilingual	Native or Bilingual
French	
Limited Working	